Guide to the Douglass Cecil North Papers, 1942-2012 and undated RL.00955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1953-2012 and undated; 6
  - Writings by Others, 1965-2001 and undated; 5
    - Brady, David and Epstein, David. Intra-Party Preferences, Heterogeneity, and the Origins of the Modern Congress: Progressive Reformers in the House and Senate, 1890-1920, undated (Box 71)
    - Brennan, Geoffrey and Buchanan, James M. The Logic of the Levers: The Pure Theory of Electoral Preference, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Bredahl, Maury, Shmitz, Andrew,and Hillman, Jimmye S. Rent Seeking in International Trade: The Great Tomato War, 1987 (Box 71)
    - Brody, Richard A. Daily News and the Dynamic of Public Support for the President, 1986 (Box 71)
    - Buchanan, James M. Victorian Budgetary Norms, Keynesian Advocacy, and Modern Fiscal Policy, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Calvert, Randall. Ahistorical Equilibria in Repeated Games of Incomplete Information with Applications to the Prisoner's Dilemma, 1985 (Box 71)
    - Calvert, Randall. Coordination and Power: The Foundation of Leadership among Rational Legislators, 1987 (Box 71)
    - Camerer, Colin. Do Biases in Probability Judgement Matter in Markets? 1987 (sixth draft) (Box 71)
    - Camerer, Colin, Lowenstein, George and Weber, Martin. The Curses of Knowledge in Economic Settings: An Experimental Analysis, 1987 (second draft) (Box 71)
    - Cameron, David R. Impact of Political Institutions of Public Sector Expansion, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Cameron, Rondo. Economic History, Pure and Applied, 1976 (Box 71)
    - Cameron, Rondo. Europe's Second Logistic, 1970 (Box 71)
    - Cameron, Rondo. A New View of European Industrialization, 1975 (Box 71)
    - Campbell, Claudia Ruth. Deposit Insurance and Risk Exposure in Commercial Banks, undated (Box 72)
    - Campbell, Donald E.: Arrow's Theorem for Economic Environments, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Campbell, Donald E.: Continuous Preferences and Arrow's Independence Axiom, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Campbell, Donald E.: Wilson's Theorem for Economic Environments, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Carhill, Mike. The Dual-Decision Hypothesis in Light of Recent Developments, 1987 - draft (Box 72)
    - Caskey, John. Latin American Debt Restructuring and the IF, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Chambers, Edward and Gordon, Donald. Some Further Reflections on the Staple Thesis, 1978 (Box 72)
    - Chamlee-Wright, Emily. The Cultural and Political Economy of Recovery., 2009 (Box 90)
    - Chatterjee, Kalyan and Samuelson, William. Bargaining Under Incomplete Information, 1983 (Box 72)
    - Cheung, Steven N.S. The Enforcement of Property Rights in Children, and the Marriage Contract, 1972 (Box 72)
    - Cheung, Steven N.S. Negative Dowry, Blind Marriage, and the Role of Ethics, 1970 (Box 72)
    - Cheung, Steven N.S. The Structure of a Contract and the Theory of a Non-exclusive Resource, 1970 (Box 72)
    - Cheung, Steven N.S. Property Rights and Invention, undated (Box 72)
    - Cheung, Steven N.S. Transaction Costs, Risk Aversion, and the Choice of Contractual Arrangements, undated (Box 72)
    - Cho, Shin. Control over Management Through Concentrated Ownership, 1988 (Box 72)
    - Clapham, J.H. Economic History in: Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, undated (Box 72)
    - Clark, Gregory. Why Isn't The Whole World Developed? Lessons from the Cotton Mills, 1986 (Box 72)
    - Clark, Gregory. Risk, Impatience and Open Field Agriculture, 1985 (Box 72)
    - Clark, Gregory, Carter, Antony T, Fox-Genovese, Elisabeth and Johansson, S. Ryan. Does Culture Matter? An Exchange, 1988 (Box 72)
    - Clingermayer, James C. Consumer, Advocacy, Regulatory Uncertainty, and the Cost of Capital: The Case of Privately-owned Electric Utilities in the U.S, 1985 (Box 72)
    - Coase, R. H. The Problem of Social Cost, 1960 Oct. (Box 72)
    - Coase, R. H. 50th anniversary lectures on the Nature of the Firm, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Coase, Ronald H. and Wang, Ning. Several Writings., 2008-2011 (Box 90)
      Includes Ning Wang's Vita.
    - Coatsworth, John H. Railroad Social Savings and Mexican Economic Growth, 1970 (Box 72)
    - Cochran, Thomas C. Economic History: Old and New, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Cochran, Thomas C. Toward a Useful Model for Social Change, 1970 (Box 72)
    - Coelho, Philip R.P. An Examination into the Causes of Economic Growth, undated (Box 72)
    - Cohen, Daniel and Sachs, Jeffrey. Growth and External Dept under Risk of Debt Repudiation, 1985 (Box 72)
    - Coleman, Jules: A Bargaining Theory Approach to Default Provisions and Disclosure Rules in Contract Law, undated (Box 72)
    - Coleman, Jules: Competition and Cooperation, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Cook, Richard E: The Effectiveness of Insider Trading Regulation, 1987 (Box 72)
    - Cook, Richard E: Proposal: The Regulation of Insider Trading, 1987 Sept. 12 (Box 72)
    - Cowgill, George L. On the Causes and Consequences of Ancient and Modern Population Changes, 1974 (Box 73)
    - Cox, Donald C. Motives for Private Income Transfers, 1985 (Box 73)
    - Cox, Donald and Nye, John Vincut. Male-Female Wage Discrimination, 1986 (Box 73)
    - Crutchfield, James A. Resource Management Strategies, 1974 (Box 73)
    - Crouzet, François. Second Thoughts About a Comparison: Britain and France in the 18th Century Revisited, 1987 (Box 73)
    - Crouzet, François. Toward an Export Economy: British Exports During the Industrial Revolution, 1980 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. Information Standards, Social Networks and the Wealth and Diversity of Nations, 1988 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. The Hero and the Herd in Technological History: Reflections on Thomas Edison and 'The Battle of the Systems', 1987 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. The Reaper and the Robot, 1984 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. Labor Productivity in English Agriculture, 1971 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. The Use and Abuse of Prior Information in Economic History, 1971 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. Transport Innovation and Economic Growth: Professor Fogel on and off the Rails, 1968 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. The Marshallian Dynamics of Industrial Localization: Chicago 1850-1890, undated (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. and Sundstrom, William. Bargains, Bequests, and Births, 1984 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. and Olsen, Trond E. Anticipated Automation: A Rational Expectations Model of Technical Diffusion, 1984 (Box 73)
    - David, Paul A. and Temin, Peter. Explaining the Relative Efficiency of Slave Agriculture in the Antebellum South Comment, 1977 (Box 73)
    - Day, Richard H. Instability in the Transition from Manoralism: A Classical Analysis, 1980 (Box 73)
    - De Alessi, Louis and Staaf, Robert J. Subjective Value in Contract Law, 1989 (Box 73)
    - Demsetz, Harold. The Growth of Government, undated (Box 73)
    - Demsetz, Harold. The Theory of the Firm Revisited, draft 1987 (Box 73)
    - Dennen, Taylor. A Note on the Efficiency Effects on the Federal Land Disposition System, undated (Box 73)
    - Denison, Edward F. Explanations of Declining Productivity Growth, 1979 (Box 73)
    - Dick, Trevor J. O. (Box 74)
    - Canadian Wheat Production and Trade, 1976 (Box 74)
    - A Model of Early 20th Century Industrial Expansion with an Application to Canadian Newsprint, 1974 (Box 74)
    - The Specification of Institutional Change in the 19th Century Canadian Economy, 1974 (Box 74)
    - United States Railroad Inventions Investment Since 1870, 1974 (Box 74)
    - Institutions, Growth and Welfare in the Canadian Past, 1971 (Box 74)
    - Dries, Marie. Asking the Great (Economic) Questions. Beloit College Magazine., 2009 (Box 90)
    - Dudley, Leonard. Punishment, Reward and the Fortunes of the State, 1989 (Box 74)
    - Dudley, Leonard. Technological Change in Interdependent Bureaucracies: Was Rome's Failure Economic or Military? undated (Box 74)
    - Easterlin, Richard A. The Economics and Sociology of Fertility: A Synthesis, 1978 (Box 74)
    - Easterlin, Richard A. Factors in the Decline of Farm Family Fertility in the United States: Some Preliminary Results, 1975 (Box 74)
    - Easterlin, Richard A. Population Change and Farm Settlement in Northern United States, 1976 (Box 74)
    - Easterlin, Richard A. Population Issues in American Economic History: A Survey and Critique, 1976 (Box 74)
    - Eavey, Cheryl L. and Miller, Gary J. Constitutional Conflict in State and Nation, 1987 (Box 74)
    - The Economics of Public Issues, 5th ed, 1979 (Box 74)
    - The Economics of Imperialism: Britain and the Colonies, 1860-1914, undated (Box 74)
    - Efficiency and Distribution in the Analysis of Collective Decisions: A Critique of Davis and North, undated (Box 74)
    - Eggertsson, Thrainn. Economic Behavior and Institutions: Property Rights, Transaction Costs and Agency: A Survey, 1987 (Box 74)
    - Eggertsson, Thrainn. Economic Problems and Policies of Iceland: The Tragedy of the Commons? 1985 (Box 74)
    - Eichengreen, Barry International Policy Coordination in Historical Perspective: A View from the Interwar Years, 1984 (Box 74)
    - Ellickson, Robert C. A Hypothesis of Wealth-maximizing Norms, 1987 (chapter draft of unidentified book) (Box 74)
    - Ellickson, Robert C. Of Coase and Cattle: Dispute Resolution among Neighbors in Shasta County, 1986 (Box 74)
    - Elliot, J.M. The Decline of Spain, 1961 (Box 74)
    - Engermann, Stanley L. Contract Labor, Sugar, and Technology in the Nineteenth Century, 1983 (Box 74)
    - Engermann, Stanley L. The Structure of the Cotton Economy of the Antebellum South, 1970 (Box 74)
    - Estiban, Javier Cuenca. The U.S. Balance of Payments with Spanish America and the Philippine Islands, 1790-1819, undated (Box 75)
    - The Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis. The Regional Economist, vol 20, No. 2, 2012 (Box 90)
    - Feeny, David. The Development of Property Rights in Land: A Comparative Study, 1988 (Box 75)
    - Fenoaltea, Stefano. Authority, Efficiency, and Agricultural Organization in Medieval England and Beyond: A Hypothesis, 1975 (Box 75)
    - Fenoaltea, Stefano. The Economics of the Common Fields, 1986 (Box 75)
    - Fenoaltea, Stefano. Authority, Efficiency, and Agricultural Organization in Medieval England and Beyond: A Hypothesis, 1975 (Box 75)
    - Fenoaltea, Stefano. Slavery and Supervision in Comparative Perspective: A Model, 1984 (Box 75)
    - Fenno, Richard F. The House Appropriations Committee as a Political System: The Problem of Integration, 1962 (Box 75)
    - Field, Alexander J. The Analysis of Association and Collective Action using Rational Choice Models, undated (Box 75)
    - Findlay, Ronald and Wilson, John D. The Political Economy of Leviathan, 1984 (Box 75)
    - Fishback, Price V. Were Coal Company Stores Exploitative? Theory and Evidence from the Early 1900s, 1985 (Box 75)
    - Fisher, Franklin M. and Temin, Peter. Regional Specialization and the Supply of Wheat in the U.S, undated (Box 75)
    - Fishlow, Albert. Comparative Consumption Patterns, the Extent of the Market, and Alternative Development Strategies, Reprint from 1973 (Box 75)
    - Floud, Roderick. The Physical State of the British Working Class, 1870-1914: Evidence from Army Recruits, 1985 (Box 75)
    - Floud, Roderick. The Heights of Europeans since 1750: A New Source for European Economic History, 1984 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. The Conquest of High Morality and Hunger in Europe and America: Timing and Mechanisms, 1988 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. Nutrition and the Decline in Mortality since 1700: Some Preliminary Findings, 1985 (Box 75)
      1 of 2.
    - Fogel, Robert W. Nutrition and the Decline in Mortality Since 1700: Some Preliminary Findings, 1985 (Box 75)
      2 of 2.
    - Fogel, Robert W. Circumstantial Evidence in 'Scientific' and Traditional History, 1981 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. Notes on the Social Savings Controversy, 1979 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. Cliometrics and Culture: Some Recent Developments in the Historiography of Slavery, 1976 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. Historiography and Retrospective Econometrics, 1970 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. The Efficiency Effects of Federal Land Policy during the 19th Century, 1969 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. The Specification Problem in Economic History, 1967 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Robert W. and Engerman, Stanley L. Philanthropy at Bargain Prices: Notes on the Economics of Gradual Emancipation, 1974 (Box 76)
    - Fogel, Robert W. and Engerman, Stanley L. A Model for the Explanation of Industrial Expansion during the Nineteenth Century: With an Application to the American Iron Industry, 1969 (Box 76)
    - Fogel, Robert W, Engerman, Stanley L. et al. The Economic and Demographic Significance of Secular Changes in Human Stature: The U.S. 1750-1960, 1979 (Box 76)
    - Fraile, Pedro. The Sectoral Role of Spain's IS Industry, 1900-1950, 1983 (Box 76)
    - Fraumeni, Barbara M. and Jorgenson, Dale W. The Role of Capital in U.S. Economic Growth, 1948-1979, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno. On Fairness of Pricing, 1987 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno. Economists Favor the Price System - Who Else Does? 1986 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno. A Public Choice Approach to Industrial Choice, 1986 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno. State and Prospects of Public Choice: A European View, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno. Politometrics of Government Behavior in a Democracy, 1979 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno and Eichenberger, Reiner E. Are Kahneman, Tversky and Co. Relevant for Economics? 1988 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno and Foppa, Klaus. Human Behavior: Possibilities Explain Action, 1986 (Box 76)
    - Frey, Bruno and Schneider, Friedrich. International Political Economy: A Rising Field, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Furubotn, Eirik G. Codetermination, Productivity Gains, and the Economics of the Firm, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Galenson, David W. The Rise and Fall of Indentured Servitude in the Americas: An Economic Analysis, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Gallman, Robert E. The U.S. Capital Stock in the Nineteenth Century, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Gallman, Robert E. The Social Distribution of Wealth in the United States of America, 1966 (Box 76)
    - Ganev, Georgy. Where Has Marxism Gone? Gauging the Impact of Alternative Ideas in Transition Bulgaria., 2005 (Box 90)
    - Garcia, Valeriano F. Monetarismo y crisis economica, Argentina 1978-1981, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Gately, Dermot. Sharing the Gains from Customs Unions Among Less Developed Countries: A Game Theoretic Approach, 1974 (Box 76)
    - Gauthier, Bernard. Agency Problems and Structural Arrangements Within International Economic Organizations: The Case of the World Bank, 1990 (Box 76)
    - Gilligan, Thomas W. The Competitive Effects of Resale Price Maintenance, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Gilligan, Thomas W, Marshall, William and Weingast, Barry R. "A Reconsideration of the Railroad Problem: The Economics and Politics of the Interstate Commerce Act, 1986 (Box 76)
    - Goldberg, Victor P. Bridges Over Contested Terrain: Exploring the Radical Account of the Employment Relationship, 1980 (Box 76)
    - Goldberg, Victor P. The Law and Economics of Vertical Restrictions: A Relational Perspective, undated (Box 76)
    - Goldin, Claudia Monitoring Costs and Occupational Segregation by Sex: A Historical Analysis, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Goldin, Claudia. Female Labor Form and American Economic Growth, 1890 to 1980, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Goldin, Claudia. Life Cycle Labor Force Participation of Married Women: Historical Evidence and Implications, 1983 (Box 76)
    - Goldin, Claudia. The Historical Evolution of Female Earnings Functions and Occupations, 1975 (Box 76)
    - Goldin, Claudia and Parsons, Donald. Parental Altruism and Child Labor, 1984 (Box 77)
    - Goldin, Claudia and Lewis, F. The Economic Cost of the American Civil War, 1975 (Box 77)
    - Goodrich, Carter. Internal Improvements Reconsidered, 1970 (Box 77)
    - Goodwin, Thomas H. and Sauer, Raymond D. Faculty Salaries and the Temporal Distribution of Research Output, 1989 (Box 77)
    - Granovetter, Mark. Economic Action and Social Structures: The Problem of Embeddedness, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Greif, Avner. Reputation and Economic Institutions in Medieval Trade: Evidences from the Geniza Documents, undated (Box 77)
    - Grenadier, Steven R., Malenko, Andrey and Strebulaev, Ilya A., 2011 (Box 90)
    - Grofman, Bernard and Scarrow, Howard A. The Riddle of Apportionment: Equality of What? 1981 (Box 77)
    - Grossman, H. and Can Huyck, John B. Sovereign Debt as a Contingent Claim: Excusable Default, Repudiation and Reputation, 1985 (Box 77)
    - The Growth and Decay of Custom: The Role of the New Institutional Economics in Economic History, 1986? (Box 77)
    - Gunderson, Gerald. The Growth and Decay of Custom: The Role of the New Institutional Economics in Economic History, 1976 (Box 77)
    - Gunderson, Gerald. The Framework of Economic Conflict Resolution and the Coming of the American Revolutionary War, undated (Box 77)
    - Gwartney, James, Stroup, Richard L. and Lee, Dwight R. Common Sense Economics., 2005 (Box 90)
    - Haber, S, Razo, A. and Maurer N. Political Instability, Credible Commitments and Economic Growth: Evidence from Revolutionary Mexico, 2000 (Box 77)
    - Haggard, Stephen and McCubbins, Matthew D. Presidents, Parliaments and Policy, 1999 July (Box 90)
    - Hammond, Thomas H. and Knott, Jack H. A Formal Model of Subgovernment Power in the Policymaking Process, 1987 (Box 77)
    - Harley, C. Knick. Prerequisites to Industrialization and their Substitutes: Comparative Institutions and Performance, 1988 (Box 77)
    - Harley, C. Knick British Foreign Trade Before the First World War, undated (Box 77)
    - Harley, C. Knick. On the Persistence of Old Techniques in the Face of Advancing Technology, undated (Box 77)
    - Hart, Keith. Rural-Urban Migration in West Africa, 1987 Jan. 13 (Box 77)
    - Hartwell, R. M. Entrepreneurship and Public Inquiry: The Growth of Government in 19th Century Britain, undated (Box 77)
    - Hartwell, R. M. and Higgs, Robert. Good Old Economic History, 1971 (Box 77)
    - Hayami, Yujiro and Ruttan, V.W. Factor Prices and Technical Change in Agricultural Development: The United States and Japan, 1880-1960, 1969 (Box 77)
    - Hayami, Yujiro, Miller, Barbara, Wade, William and Yamashita, Saschiko. An International Comparison of Agricultural Production and Productivities, 1971 (Box 77)
    - Hechter, Michael. A Theory of Group Solidarity, 1980 (Box 77)
    - Heijdra, Ben J, Lowenberg, A.D. and Mallick, R.J. Marxism, Methodological Individualism, and the New Institutional Economics, 1987 (Box 77)
    - Heiner, Ronald A. The Origins of Predictable Behavior, 1980 (Box 77)
    - Heiner, Ronald A. The Origins of Predictable Dynamic Behavior, 1988 (Box 77)
    - Heiner, Ronald A. Experimental Economics: Comment, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Heiner, Ronald A. Imperfect Decisions in Organizations, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Higgs, Robert: (Box 78)
    - Accumulation of Property by Southern Blacks Before World War I, 1982 (Box 78)
    - Crisis, Bigger Government and Ideological Change: Two Hypotheses on the Ratchet Phenomenon, undated (Box 78)
    - On Ideology as an Analytical Concept, book-chapter; undated (Box 78)
    - The Sources of Big Government, 1982 (Box 78)
    - The Trend Lines for Leviathan: An Analytical Perspective, 1982 (Box 78)
    - Higgs, Robert and Stettler, H. Louis. Colonial New England Demography: A Sampling Approach, 1988 (Box 78)
    - Hirsch, Paul M. and Lounsbury, Michael D. Book Review Essay: Rediscovering Volition: The Institutional Economics of Douglass C. North., 1996 (Box 90)
    - Hirshleifer, Jack. Privacy: Its Origins, Function and Future, 1980 (Box 78)
    - Hoff, Karla and Stiglitz, Joseph E. Equilibrium Fictions: A Cognitive Approach to Societal Rigidity., 2010 (Box 90)
    - Hoffman, Philip T. Social History and Agricultural Productivity in France, 1450-1789, 1989 (Box 78)
    - Hoffman, Elizabeth and Spitzer, M. L. Entitlements, Rights and Fairness: Some Experimental Results, 1983 (Box 78)
    - Huber, Richard. The Effect on Prices of Japan's Entry Into World Commerce After 1858, reprint from 1971 (Box 78)
    - Hughes, Jonathan. Roots of Regulation - The New Deal, undated (Box 78)
    - Hughes, Jonathan. Transference and Development of Institutional Constraints upon Economic Activity, undated (Box 78)
    - Hughes, Jonathan. The Cadre Adonis - A Bourgeoise Rationary View, 1970 (Box 78)
    - Hussain, Akmal. An Institutional Framework for Inclusive Growth., 2009 (Box 90)
    - Hutchison, W.T. "Book Review: On Revolutions and Progress in Economic Knowledge," 1979 (Box 78)
    - Incomplete Paper on Economics of Mitigating Malaria and HIV/AIDS. Author Unknown., Approx. 2002 (Box 90)
    - Inman, Robert P. Fiscal Allocations in a Federalist Economy: Understanding in the New Federalism, undated (Box 78)
    - James, John A. and Skinner, Jonathan. The Resolution of the Labor Scarcity Paradox, 1984 (Box 78)
    - James, John A. Shifts in the 19th Century Phillips Curve Relationship, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Jay, Peter. The Wealth of Man., 2000 (Box 90)
    - Jensen, Michael and Meckling, William H. Theory of the Firm: Managerial Behavior, Agency Costs, and Ownership Structure, 1976 (Box 78)
    - Johansson, S. Ryan. The Computer Paradigm and the Role of Cultural Information in Social Systems, 1988 (Box 78)
    - Johnson, Noel and La Fountain, Courtney. Immigrant Participation in U. S. Elections., 2007 (Box 90)
    - Johnson, Ronald and Libecap, Gary D. Contracting Problems and Regulations: The Case of the Fishery, 1982 (Box 78)
    - Jones, E.L. Institutional Determinism and the Rise of the Western World, 1973 (Box 78)
    - Jones, Homer. Banking Reform in the 1930s, 1977 (Box 78)
    - Jones, Charles I. And Romer, Paul M. The New Kaldor Facts: Ideas, Institutions, Population and Human Capital., 2009 (Box 90)
    - Kalai, Ehud. Artificial Decisions and Strategic Complexity in Repeated Games, 1987 (Box 78)
    - Kearl, J.R. and Pope, Clayne L. Unobservable Family and Individual Contributions to the Distribution of Income and Wealth, 1984 (Box 78)
    - Kahan, Arcadius. Notes on Serfdom in Western and Eastern Europe, undated (Box 78)
    - Kenessey, Zoltan. The Premature Post-Industrial Syndrome, undated (Box 78)
    - Kinship and Stratification, Appendix - undated (Box 79)
    - Knight, J.B. and Sabot, R.H. Lewis Through a Looking Glass: Public Sector Employment, Rent-seeking and Economic Growth, 1988 (Box 79)
    - Kochan, Thomas A. and Bazerman, Max H. Macro Determinants of the Future, 1986 (Box 79)
    - Kochin, Lewis H. The Problem of Social Cost and the Transaction Costs..., 1986 (Box 79)
    - Koford, Kenneth. Different Preferences, Different Politics: A Reinterpretation of Lowi's Typology, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Koford, Kenneth. A Multidimensional Framework for Centralized Vote-trading and Agenda Control, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Koford, Kenneth. Scale Economies and Rent Seeking in Legislative Parties, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Kopczuk, Wojciech and Slemrod, Joel. Denial od Death and Economic Behavior., 2005 (Box 91)
    - Kuran, Timur. Moral Overload and Its Alleviation, Revised 1996 (Box 79)
    - Kuran, Timur. The Tenacious Past: Theories of Personal and Collective Conservativism, 1987 (Box 79)
    - La Croix, Sumner J. and Roumasset, James. An Economic Theory of Political Change in Premissionary Hawaii, 1994 (Box 79)
    - La Croix, Sumner J. Property Rights Redistributions: A Case Study of Hawaii's Great Mahele, 1983 (Box 79)
    - Ladna, Krishna. Money in Congressional Voting, 1989 (Box 79)
    - Lal, Deepak and Patel, Urjit. Transaction Costs or the Costs of Doing Business: Empirical Estimates for Some Developing Countries, 1988 (Box 79)
    - Landa, Janet T. The Economics on Trust, Ethnicity, and Identity: Beyond Markets and Hierarchies, 1987 (Box 79)